Hello, welcome to the new episode of Learn German in Hindi.
In the last episode, we also did one examination
when we saw the Iron part. This time we are always going to see
Human. According to me, Shravan
is the easiest and most scoring type.
I myself got 99 marks in it and
for all the students who learn from me, it has always been a scoring
style. So, now we will give a little bit of its
exam pattern and its tips.
So first of all, if you are watching the exam, then
I will tell you the pattern in this general in a little less time.
What you have to do in this, you have to
write the last three things, you have to
write the message, you have to write the image and you have to write your opinion.
So first see, first you have to write a formal
email, what is that, we will see in detail. You have to
write a formal email, 80
words, means how many, 10 to 15 lines for 40 minutes. Oh,
here you have to write your opinion.
Agyeya Steward, 10 to 15 lines
for 40 minutes. And finally, you have to write this formal
email, in that you have 20 marks.
For that you have to write about 40 words i.e. five to seven
sentences, so keep this aside and you will
write 25 to 30 sentences in total, see that
whether the zoom is about six percent i.e.
pass for sixty marks and on pretty simple, where
many people make mistake is
in understanding its marking, for this,
before going into these details of these tiles, let us
understand its marking system, so first of all
you will develop a single marking system for all these three tiles, it will be
requested on 14 points, which one
we will see, first of all I will refuel
executive means technically it is a full
film, whatever test you have given, that is,
in matters of voice mail, whatever you have put in formal mail, you have
completed it,
if you have three points, then it
is written on three points, what is refueling for this,
these are your own marks, do
not pay any attention to it at all, ok,
after that next comes the coin, just
like in English, help Koyal means what is
follow and of anything
How is the decision to be taken whether you are a director,
write any sentence like this, let there be
some logical basis for what you have written, Tasmat,
here our
conjunctions will be very useful for us,
we have learnt 6 to 7 types of conjunctions,
these will be very useful for you here,
outside of that comes WhatsApp,
WhatsApp means your comparison,
how big is your vocabulary and how many
different ways do you use them and so that
means
this portion of it while using it correctly and after that, restaurant
Ural means
how correct is your grammar, do you
make any sentence in different ways and if you have made
some mistakes, after that it did
not go in the bag, then how much problem does it cause for
people to understand the meaning of your sentence,
all these are
important things for the student, understand that these four have
almost equal weightage, if you see
10104 10104 10106 dasai then  Almost everything about twenty five
percent
marks, so always remember
what happens unfortunately, generally people only pay
attention to WhatsApp but especially to the run showrooms, pay
attention to them through our route as well, if you
understand this then we look at the main details every
time, so first of all we see,
what you have to do in the first time, you have to
write an email in a formal way, if you have to
write to a friend, then in which form will you
write it, and
what happens in it generally, you have done something, that
you have done a course or it is someone's
birthday, you have come back from a trip and you will let
your friend know and
what did you like from it, and then generally you search
whether we met, that is how many days
points are there generally, you can see that in it,
now you will see, for example,
what is there in it, see, it was someone's birthday,
you have to tell your friend that brother, your friend was
not able to come, so you have to tell him
which gift I liked the most on that birthday
and in the hand means suggestion for meeting next
which is simple, right total how many
10s you get  You have to make 15 sentences, you have to cover all the three points, so
first of all you have to
write about friends, after that if you are
writing to a friend then you have to write in the beginning
because dear which is mail written in Hindi, so
liberty mail
means lemon and you can start with that,
okay and then you start, so generally speaking to give
feedback you
can say wicket diy weekend yaar, how is yours or
ist by this is not true, means
everything is going well for you, right, you can start with this
and then you can say because
friends it is simple, the first point Pritam
is simple, 11 yes brother my birthday was very nice, we
celebrated it, went to a hotel,
ate, danced, you can write anything and then at the
second point you can say that I got a lot of
gifts but the best one was from
my father, I liked it,
he gave me a gift, you can write anything,
in the simplest you can say that brother,
hey friend we can meet next Sunday,
I have also shown you the photo, that Chanel
2019 mango, jamun Stephen or if you want to
use coffee  This is B virus Wendell Holmes
Stock 53, you can do it, if you understand then it is simple here, you can
correct something in it and in the end you
can say that brother definitely say it,
special in my memory means definitely say it and
then at the end we write the system in Hindi,
similarly you can write feel kusaya libas, that
means warm regards, how can you go of
club, Russia, lever anger, that is informal
and there is
no need to write the name of the admin, that is friend, often, so you
see, the beginning is very simple, how is it
formal, so whatever the lever is,
after that do a little bit of will get addicted,
then write on all three points, while doing friend, that
time, say different,
tighten me, feeling that useless and write your name,
remember the information from the net,
take it from another, it is very simple, right next which is till now
or the neck tile is very simple,
what you have to do in this also, generally
you are given a condition that you have
watched some TV program or
watched some program online and on that
you  You have to write your opinion online and
you have to write it in 15 lines from Asimanand only
and what he has done is
see you have an active theme as well and
below that there is an opinion of some other topic,
what is the important thing right now, that guy
's app opens, this is just for your help,
if you do not understand the meaning or thing, if
you are
not understanding some of the logic in your words, for that you do
not have to react to that side person because the name, you do not need to think about the
biggest mistake people did, you do not even think, especially
mine, some people believed that
I used to do something like that,
Sardar, if you understand the theme correctly after seeing it, there is
no need to read the theme below and if you are not able to
understand it then you can see below, it is
important,
I have nothing to do with it, you have
written for in it, hence you do not need to write anything else, you will
see against development, he has nothing to do with it.  Do
n't do it, if you have to do it then what
you have to do is when you have to write it, it is
very simple, any date I have just mentioned here
that festival and badminton means what is
fixed work timing, then you have to write that topic
very simple, what is your opinion, what is the
advantage of this, another house
decided, if you want to learn English then friend I
can say in summary I want to see the, it is
very simple, very important thing, from
which side do you say it, nobody cares, I mean you can
say it like this also because it seems to me that
fixing and backward class families,
very good, firstly do your work, do your work, go
home, you have your own schedule,
you know what I will do and when, you can
set your meeting with the client, in the morning I know
what to do, in the evening also I know
what to do, I can make my time table, still
if yes sometimes there is a problem, if there is
some problem then I can take leave, you
can write that also, or not, I
think so, but when the lining is good, when I feel like it
I will work in the morning and then at
night. It's in October.
Raju Saini has flexibility. Then I can
decide if I have an emergency,
I can go and work in the afternoon.
I don't need to take leave for that.
Like, and I think I can
work much more productively, focusing on
whatever your gut is.
What's important is
writing your opinion properly. I
can differentiate it and return it. Advantages to
create a culture which I can't give to anyone. I can
think differently from others. I don't know what to do with it.
I used to do it myself. I know this.
Good, and I knew this
humor and I believe that you can
put your point across to consumers, etc. Then you can say that this gift
flop is fertile. There are many romantic ones,
which I have to write another one. First, it
feels naturally tasty. The last match will
also be Jhalaar. And my favorite is the
vitamin crop, Mr. Jalandhar. I mean, we will link
time in this summary and say it again.  I would like to say
that now you can say my simple one meaning
you just have to understand the thing if you
understood it directly it is good if you did not understand then you
can spend time on it below
see that there is no difference in it you can be
confident enough directly in this direction if you are not confident enough then
you can take some words etc. from her husband
but do not copy I do not want
help in understanding in India and World
Complete I have written my own that all this can be done right now
so if you have to
write a formal letter it is for Bismarck you have to write 5 to 7
lines you have to write 40 words the
concept is that
someone has given you an appointment
and you cannot come say sorry or say I will
come later or you have to
set an appointment with someone my
simple drawing right now this is formal so
how will you do it you will do it on the phone
and how will you start for that this
question is if the general has given the name of the same person then if
she is a lady then every tapra of poison
Hooda if she  If you are a gentleman then you
can use your daughter's name, if you have
n't given the name then like in English letters
Sir and Madam, similarly you
can use your name here, okay
this is just the beginning, this is a formal letter,
so there is no need to break the ice, it's a
straight point, how is it here yet that
someone has invited you to a party,
you cannot come there, you have asked him to give the reasoning, and
if you want both, you can say that I will
come on Monday, so it's very simple, very simple,
then the alarm, thank you, I was called
to the institute, you can say allied, right, you
can point to it in the next code, enter minister of etc. If you will
use collector here too, then because you can
say 800, which thing is very simple and in the end
because if these are formal
with friend requests, you can ask like this,
minute from English and Roshan meet finally
Singh Roshan complete, not that formal, the character is very
simple, at very  Simple 5 to 7
sister you just have to write Most
likely that's just sorry I can't come
because I missed this the forest
ok Khan you will understand so if you have
understood the format then let's see some tips
it is very simple if you have
written 5 sentences in normal form then there is
no need to do anything different what will you
do this laser will be a very
big super set of it and if you have done conjunctions till now then it is very important
that I mobile van rompoy
if you know all this then it is very useful
if it is possible then on any that website also
you will take two papers time its side call
one traditional call so it is good but not really
including 11 pattern handset then you
can do that ok Khan also in these exams
the most important thing is that you
have side minutes engine juice 8 minutes of income
because how many you get about
twenty five 230 maximum thirty five
lines but there are and you know all round what is going to happen,
so I will activate it,
quickly read everything calmly, understand what you have to do, take a
break in every task, then
make points for it, I don't believe that at least there is
no need to write the entire beginning, but the
points that you are going to make, at least
write a cross once in the box, what is it like we used to do
in school, not by adding and going there and
writing, then it does not look good if it is turned off, wait
a bit, do it first and then write
in the order in which you have to write, first second third third second
first, this pack activated
for me, use it, first if it is
written 123, then after writing the first one, do
not go to check it, that way mistakes are
not visible, first write one very carefully, then go to the
settings, answer one two three, okay second very important
tip, do
not write too much, that is, he has written 80 years, make it 90, show the maximum, do
not write the exam date message,
I have deliberately, if you will see on the screen that
this is the same,
yes, this crispy answer sheet sample answer
face, look at how small they are, these
Remember, there is no need to see it completely, it is
destined to be that small, so if you
write more than 10, say, Pranam and Lions, that is, 10 to 15, then the main problem is that you will make more
mistakes,
so do not take too much, ok,
otherwise, the important thing is to write your
contacts, understand that people often have the
habit of using very big words, as I said, this is a
good thing from WhatsApp, but just a part of
all the scheme, 25 percent mode, iron, simple yellow
flowers, new, important, sometimes, it is an option
because I like this word, that is
why people want to put it, it is Don Dawood,
this gives you normal proof, Ekta, ₹500 are
going well, it is a good thing, but it is
not just a WhatsApp liquor, do not forget this,
what is important is that you do not
sit breaking all the points, it is
very important because of this, I
said that first I have to write on the point,
if you wrote 10-12 lines on how our birthday was so good
And if you
don't talk about fashion then there is a problem Smriti Kanwar,
first read all the points in All Girl Talk
calmly, that is the most
important and lastly
my favorite tip for myself is to spend at least 5 minutes
with Ayush, 5 minutes if possible, 10 minutes
in the last just for chatting, for
checking with a calm mind and what
we have to check there is that the jewellery is mostly
written in English, so the
normal capitals in English are not capitalized
but in German, you will have to
check that it is normal, it can go wrong,
then check the spelling, then it is very
important when you write both the words, it
seems correct that they are written, so that is why
calmly check that all those sections are properly
conserved, if you have
used collectors like viral, then see that the one which is
going to go waste,
and that tweet, no matter how much you practice, there will be
some mistakes there, this is a
plate and while writing you do not remember it
for you  Calmly, if there is
no extra foot Faizabad Express then that is
why we will do it again, police
checking is very important, the more you
correct your own mistakes, the more you will
save your way, that
mute examiner was going to throw out one side, did you
understand, if you have done this much then it is
very straight forward and you have enough
time, you know almost what to do, you
can go after practicing, you have to
remain calm there, just write all the points
logically, if you come and mix it, that you are
not making half unnecessary grammatical mistakes, then it is purely very easy and
scoring topic, I hope you have understood this very well,
in the next lesson we will discuss about
10th